<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="notes_content">
        <item> How to Report an Emergency \n\n\n

1. Assess the urgency of the situation. Before you report an emergency, make sure the situation is genuinely urgent. Call for emergency services if you believe that a situation is life-threatening or otherwise extremely disruptive. Here are some genuine emergencies you should report:
        \n
        ● A crime, especially one that is currently in progress.
        \n
        ● A fire.
        \n
        ● A life-threatening medical emergency that requires immediate attention.
        \n
        ● A car crash.
        \n\n
        2. Call emergency services. The emergency number varies by country. In Malaysia, its 999 and 112.
        \n\n
        3. Report your location. The first thing the emergency dispatcher will ask is where you are located, so the emergency services can get there as quickly as possible. Give the exact street address, if possible; if you are not sure of the exact address, give approximate information.
        \n\n
        4. Give the dispatcher your phone number. This information is also imperative for the dispatcher to have, so she or he is able to call back if necessary.
        \n\n
        5. Describe the nature of the emergency. Speak in a calm, clear voice and tell the dispatcher why you are calling. Give the most important details first, then answer the dispatchers follow-up questions as best you can.
        \n
        ● If you are reporting a crime, give a physical description of the person committing the crime.
        \n
        ● If you are reporting a fire, describe how the fire started and where exactly it is located. If someone has already been injured or is missing, report that as well.
        \n
        ● If you are reporting a medical emergency, explain how the incident occurred and what symptoms the person currently displays.
        \n\n
        6. Follow the dispatchers instructions. After the dispatcher has gathered all the necessary information, she or he may tell you to assist the person or people in need. You may receive instructions on how to give emergency medical treatment, such as CPR. Pay careful attention, and do not hang up the phone until you are instructed to do so. Then follow the instructions you were given.
        \n\n
        7. Remain on the line until you are told to hang up. Even if you can not keep the phone to your ear or on loudspeaker, you should still keep your phone on and not terminate the call.
        \n\n
        8. Hang up the call when instructed to do so by the dispatcher. If its necessary to make another call, then you can do so. Just follow the steps in this article again.
        \n\n </item>


        <item>
                How to Handle an Emergency Situation
                \n\n\n
                1. Remain calm. Although emergencies require rapid action, the most important factor in effectively handling the situation is to keep calm. If you find yourself becoming confused or anxious, stop what you re doing. Take a few deep breaths to help yourself relax. Remember that to be calm in a stressful situation you must deliberately adjust your behavior. Acting calm will also help other people nearby relax as well. Reassure yourself that you can handle the situation.
                \n\n
                ● The reason you feel panicked in an emergency is the result of your body s automatic overproduction of the stress hormone cortisol. The cortisol goes to the brain and slows down the prefrontal cortex, which is the region responsible for planning complex action.
                \n
                ● By overriding your body s reaction, you can continue to access your critical thinking faculties. You won t be responding from emotion but from rational thought. Look around and assess the situation to see what needs to be done before acting.
                \n\n
                2. Seek additional help. Call for an emergency number.This phone number will reach an emergency dispatcher who will need to know your location and the nature of the emergency.
                \n\n
                ● Answer all of the questions the dispatcher asks. The job of the dispatcher is to provide quick, appropriate emergency response. She can only do this by asking these questions.
                \n
                ● If you re calling on a traditional telephone or a GPS-equipped cell phone, emergency services may be able to track your location even if you re unable to speak. Even if you can t talk, call emergency services and someone will be able to find you to provide help.
                \n
                ● It may be a good idea to go over how you would communicate during an emergency, especially if you have a reason to expect an emergency might arise.
                \n\n

                3.Determine the nature of the emergency. What signs indicate that there is an emergency? Is this a medical emergency, or is there a threat to the property/building that may result in human injury? It s important to stop and take inventory of the situation calmly before reacting to the emergency.
                \n\n
                 An injury due to a motor vehicle accident, smoke inhalation, or burns from a fire are examples of medical emergency situations.
                \n
                 A medical emergency consists of sudden physical symptoms, such as seizure, intense bleeding, head trauma, loss of consciousness, chest pain, lack of breath or pulse, choking, sudden dizziness, or weakness.
                \n
                 Intense desire to hurt yourself or someone else constitutes a mental health emergency.
                \n
                 Other mental health changes may also be considered an emergency, such as sudden changes in behavior or experiencing confusion, which can be an emergency if they occur without cause.
                \n
                 Behavioral emergencies are best met by remaining calm, watching from a short distance, and encouraging the person in crisis to stay calm as well. This way you can react appropriately if the situation becomes volatile.
                \n
                4. Know that sudden changes can be emergencies. Chemical spills, fires, breaking water pipes, electrical outages, natural disasters such as floods or fires are all examples of potential workplace emergencies. If you have advanced warning of the possibility of an emergency, such as the warning of a flood, heavy snow, tornado, etc., you may be better prepared. However, the nature of an emergency is to be unexpected.
                \n\n
                ● When assessing emergency situations, be aware that the situation may be volatile. It may change rapidly.
                \n
                ● If you have advance warning of an emergency, prepare ahead of time for the best results.
                \n\n
                5. Be alert for human-caused emergencies. Assaults or threats of violence at a workplace or home are emergencies that call for rapid response. In most cases, there are no predictable patterns or methods for these emergencies. These situations tend to be unpredictable, and they change quickly.[4]
                \n\n
                ● If you find yourself in an emergency of this nature, keep yourself safe. Run to a safe location, or find shelter in place. Do not fight, except as a last resort.
                \n
                ● Being attentive to warning signs in your workplace, including any act of physical violence (pushing, shoving, etc.) should be immediate. Your office should have a procedure for workplace violence, including a phone number you can call to report the situation. If you don t know your office s procedures, ask your supervisor or a trusted coworker.
                \n
                ● Open, honest communication between employees and supervisors is part of maintaining a safe, healthy workplace.
                \n\n
                6. Assess the immediate threat. For example, if one person appears injured, are you or anyone else in danger of also being injured? For example, if one person is caught in a machine, is the machine turned off? If there has been a chemical spill, is the spill spreading towards anyone else? Is the person caught in a structure that s collapsing?
                \n
                ● If the threat isn t contained, this will affect your response.
                \n
                ● Be aware that any emergency situation may change abruptly, so ongoing assessment is required.
                \n
                7. Remove yourself from danger. If you, or others, are at risk of being harmed, leave the situation immediately. If you have an evacuation plan, follow it. Go to an area where you will be safe.
                \n\n
                ● In a situation where you cannot leave, find the safest possible location within your given area. For example, hiding beneath a solid surface, such as a desk or table, may help if there is a chance of being hit by falling debris.
                \n
                ● If you re near a car accident, make sure you re not in the line of oncoming traffic. Get off the road.
                \n
                ● Be aware that in an emergency, elements are likely to change quickly. In your assessment, notice if volatile or combustible elements are present. For example, in an auto accident, gasoline may catch fire abruptly.
                \n\n
                8. Help others leave a hazardous area. If you can safely assist someone else in leaving a dangerous situation, do so. If returning to the emergency situation is risky, a trained rescue person may be better equipped to retrieve anyone in harm s way.
                \n\n
                ● Offering verbal reassurance to an injured person if he is conscious will help another person, even if you can t move them. Let that person know who you are and what is happening to them. Ask them questions to keep them conscious.
                \n
                ●If the emergency is stable, stay with the victim.

        </item>

        <item>
                How to Communicate During an Emergency
                \n\n\n
                1. Charge your cell phone if you know an emergency is coming. If you re preparing for an emergency, charge your cell phone. Purchase a car charger to use once you run out of batteries, especially if the power may go out, and keep a few spare batteries on hand.
                \n\n
                ● If you re charging a phone with your car, never turn it on in an enclosed place. Use running cars outdoors to prevent carbon monoxide poisoning.
                \n\n
                2. Forward landlines calls to your cell phone. Contact your phone service company to ask about forwarding landline calls to your mobile phone. That way, you ll be more likely to receive all important calls during a power outage.
                \n\n
                ● If you can t reach your phone company, you may be able to activate call forwarding online or through your phone s settings.
                \n\n
                3. Subscribe to a local text alert service. Ask your local authorities about any official emergency text alert services. Sign up for any available alert services to stay updated on breaking news as it happens.
                \n\n
                ● Contact your local authorities or police for specific instructions on how to subscribe to their text alerts.
                \n
                ● Sign up for school district emergency alert services as well if you have children.
                \n\n
                4. Text instead of call whenever possible to keep the lines clear. If you have a non-emergency message during a citywide disaster, send a text message to keep the network lines clear. As long as you have service, your phone should be able to send text messages with no or minor delays.
                \n\n
                ● Because most emergency phone numbers do not offer a texting option, call them unless you know your area s emergency services offer a texting option.
                \n\n
                5. Purchase a satellite phone to use in case of emergencies. Satellite phones connect to orbiting satellites instead of grounded cell sites and can call, text, and load basic Internet sites. Switch to a satellite phone or keep one on hand in case of emergencies where landline or mobile phones may be unavailable.
                \n
                ● You can buy satellite phones online or from many electronics or outdoor survival stores.

        </item>
        <item>
How to Stop Your Car in an Emergency
                \n\n\n
                1. Immediately take your foot off of the accelerator.\n\n
                2. Quickly have your foot hovering over the brakes.\n\n
                3. Apply the clutch, this is to prevent the engine from stalling.\n\n
                4. Apply the brake immediately after applying the clutch. With the foot hovering in the air, the heel not leaning on the floor of the car, immediately apply the foot brake as hard as possible as quickly as possible. For most drivers, not having extensive training in methods like "threshold" braking or "regressive" braking, this will be the most efficient method of stopping your car quickly and controllably, regardless of road conditions or if the car has ABS or not.
                \n\n
                ● In cars with ABS, especially in slippery conditions, intervals of howling, screeching or squashing tires can be heard, alongside with pulsation in the pedal, jerks to the steering and chassis, as well as loud noises. This is normal and is indicating that the system is doing its job, slowing you down efficiently, under control, allowing better handling and less wear on the tires.
                \n
                ● In cars without ABS, a strong and constant squeal or splash sound will be emitted from the tires. The wheel will tighten up, jerk and suddenly feel lighter. There might also be a bit of smoke. The wear of the tires will not be too hard, especially in the wet. The car will not swerve or spin, since the inertia is pushing it forward. In road conditions which are slippery, or in split-grip (when two wheels are on a different surface, like a gravel or grassy shoulder), the front of the car might pull slightly sideways, but the car as a whole will keep on sliding dead ahead to a quick stop.
                \n\n
                5. Brake. If there is indeed a need to make an evasive maneuver, always begin with braking. This will slow you down, to enable this procedure to be done more efficiently and controllably, or to absorb the impact should it occur. While steering around objects is technically quicker than stopping before them, steering is not always possible, due to road conditions, speed and other cars. In the meanwhile, the car is still progressing. It is hard, though, to evade an object when braking. The tendency is to stare at it and pray to stop before it. To look away, you need to shake your head, forcing the eyes to follow it, and than focus on a visual target in a direction of possible escape. In an non-ABS car, looking away will also help to get over the urge to stay on the brakes, which disables steering.
                \n\n
                6. If there is a need to brake while turning: take out a bit of the steering input while braking.
                \n\n
                ●With ABS, brake as hard as possible, and turn as normal while braking.
                \n
                ●Without ABS, brake moderately hard (about 70%) and release the brake to turn. If you re already in a turn, don t brake too hard or you ll lock up the wheels and be unable to steer.


        </item>

        <item>

Hands-Only CPR for Adults and Teens
                \n\n\n
1. Examine the scene for any obvious hazards. In some cases, it may not be safe to perform CPR. If there are any dangers nearby preventing you from getting close to the person, don’t endanger your own life as well as theirs. Call emergency services and wait for help to arrive.
\n\n
                ● For example, if the person has collapsed due to exposure to smoke and fire or toxic fumes, steer clear of the area.
\n
                ● If the person is in a dangerous situation and you’re able to move them safely, do so before trying to give them CPR. For example, if they’ve collapsed in the middle of the street, wait for a moment when there’s no oncoming traffic and then move them out of the road.
\n\n
2. Check for unresponsiveness. If an adult or teen collapses but remains conscious, CPR is not typically needed. If they lose consciousness and are not breathing, however, you should administer rescue breaths if possible, or stick to hands-only CPR if you’re not trained in doing rescue breathing. If they’re not breathing, have no pulse, and are unresponsive, try to perform some form of CPR even if you are untrained or rusty in your abilities.
\n\n
                ● Shake the victim s shoulders and loudly ask, "Are you okay?" If you receive no response, check for signs of breathing, like the person’s chest rising and falling. Check for a pulse by placing your fingers on their carotid artery, next to the windpipe just below the jaw.
\n
                ● Hands-only CPR is ideal for those without formal CPR training or for people unsure in their CPR abilities. It does not involve the rescue breathing measures associated with conventional CPR, but instead focuses on chest compressions.
\n\n

3. Call the Emergency Services. If you find a person who is unresponsive, isn’t breathing, or doesn’t have a pulse and you decide to do some form of CPR, you should still immediately call your local emergency number before you do anything else. CPR can revive people on occasion, but it should be viewed as buying time until emergency personnel arrive with appropriate equipment.
\n\n
                ● If 2 or more people are available, 1 person should dial for help while the other begins CPR.If a person is unresponsive because of suffocation (from drowning, for example), then it s recommended to immediately begin CPR for 1 minute and then call your local emergency number.
\n
                ● If the victim is a child between the ages of 1 to 8 years, perform 5 cycles of chest compressions and rescue breathing before calling emergency services if you are the only person available. This should take roughly 2 minutes.
\n
                ● Calling emergency services will bring paramedics to the location. Typically, the dispatcher will also be able to instruct you on how to perform CPR.
\n\n

4. Keep the victim on their back. In order to perform hands-only CPR, the victim should be positioned on their back (supine), preferably on a firm surface, with the head facing up. If the person is on their side or stomach (prone), then gently roll them onto their back while trying to support their head and neck. Try to make note if the person experienced significant trauma while falling and becoming unconscious.
\n\n
                ● Once on the person is on their back, kneel next to their neck and shoulders so you have better access to their chest and mouth.
\n
                ● Keep in mind that you should not move the person if you suspect they may have suffered a significant head, neck, or spinal injury. In this case, moving them is life-threatening and should be avoided, unless emergency help won t be available for a long time (a few hours or more).
\n\n
5. Tilt the person’s chin up to open their airway. Once you have them on their back, tilt their head back while pressing their chin up and forward with 2 fingers. This should move their tongue out of the way and make it easier for them to breathe.
\n\n
                ● If you’re afraid the person has a neck injury, try not to move their head. Use both hands to carefully move their jaw forward without moving the rest of their head or neck.
\n
                ● Once you’ve opened the airway, listen carefully for sounds of breathing and check to see if their chest is rising and falling. If you can’t find any signs of breathing after about 10 seconds, or if the person is only gasping occasionally instead of breathing regularly, start CPR.


6. Rapidly push down on the center of the chest. Place one hand directly over the center of the person s chest (between their nipples, generally) and your other hand on top of the first for reinforcement. Press down on the victim s chest firmly and quickly—aim for about 100 chest compressions a minute until paramedics arrive.
\n\n
                ● Use your upper body weight and strength, not just your arm strength, to push straight down on the chest.
\n
                ● Your chest compressions should cause the person s chest to depress at least 2 inches (5.1 cm). Push hard and understand that it is likely you will break the person s ribs. This is extremely common, and you shouldn t stop compressions even if you think this has happened.
\n
                ● Chest compressions are hard work and you may have to switch off with other bystanders before emergency personnel arrive.
\n
                ● Continue doing this action until the person becomes responsive or until the emergency medical team arrives and take over.

        </item>
        <item>
Conventional CPR for Adults and Children \n\n\n

1. Follow the same initial procedures as hands-only CPR. Even if you have recent CPR training and are confident of your abilities, you still need to assess the person to see if they are responsive. Move them onto their back if they are not responsive and show no sign of neck, head, or spine injury. Try to call emergency services before starting chest compressions and look for someone to trade off with.
\n\n
                ● If performing CPR on a small child between the ages of 1 and 8 years, only use 1 hand to perform chest compressions.
                \n
                ● The rate of chest compressions is the same for both adults and children (roughly 100 per minute).
                \n
                ● For children between the ages of 1 and 8 years, you will need to depress the sternum (chest bone) 1/3 to 1/2 of the depth of the child s chest.
                \n
                ● If you have recent CPR training, perform only 30 chest compressions before moving on to the breathing assistance phase of CPR.
                \n\n
                2.Proceed to open the airway. If you re trained in CPR, confident of your abilities (not rusty), and you ve performed 30 chest compressions, then proceed to open the person s airway using the head-tilt, chin-lift technique,or the jaw-thrust if you suspect a neck/head/spine injury. Put your palm on their forehead and gently tilt (extend) their head back a little. Then, with your other hand, gently lift the chin forward to open up their airway, making it easier to give them oxygen.
                \n\n
                ● Take 5 to 10 seconds to check for normal breathing. Look for chest motion, listen for breathing, and see if you can feel the victim s breath on your cheek or ear.
                \n
                ● Note that gasping is not considered to be normal breathing.
                \n
                ● If they are already breathing, no breathing assistance is needed. However, if they are still not breathing, then proceed to the mouth-to-mouth breathing part of CPR.
                \n
                ● To perform the jaw-thrust technique, sit above the person s head. Place one hand on each side of the person s jaw and lift the jaw so that it is jutting forward, as though the person has an underbite.
                \n\n
                3.Place your mouth over the victim s mouth. Once the person s head is tilted and their chin lifted, make sure their mouth is free of any objects blocking their airway. Then, use one hand to pinch the victim s nostrils closed and cover their mouth completely with your own mouth. Form a seal with your mouth so that no air can escape while you attempt to give the victim a rescue breath.
                \n\n
                ● You should be aware that mouth-to-mouth CPR can transfer infectious viral and bacterial diseases between the victim and the rescuer.● Before contacting their mouth with yours, wipe away any vomit, mucus, or excess saliva that may be present.
                \n
                ● Rescue breathing can also be mouth-to-nose breathing if the person s mouth is seriously injured or can t be opened.
                \n
                4. Start with 2 rescue breaths. Once your mouth is over the other person s, forcefully breathe into their mouth for at least 1 full second and watch their chest to determine if it rises a little or not. If it does, give the second breath. If it doesn t, then repeat the head-tilt, chin-lift maneuver and try again. Don t be too timid or grossed out, because a person s life is in your hands.
                \n\n
                ● Although theres carbon dioxide in your breath when you exhale, there s still enough oxygen to benefit a victim during CPR. Again, the purpose isn t always to revive them or continue indefinitely, but to buy some time for them until paramedics arrive.
                \n
                ● Approximately 30 chest compressions and 2 rescue breaths is considered to be 1 cycle of conventional CPR for both adults and children.
                \n
                ● If performing CPR on a child between the ages of 1 and 8 years, you can use gentler breaths to inflate their lungs.
                \n\n
                5. Repeat cycles as needed. Follow the 2 rescue breaths with another round of 30 chest compressions and 2 more rescue breaths. Repeat as needed until the victim becomes responsive or until emergency medical personnel can take over. Remember that chest compressions attempt to restore some sort of circulation, while the rescue breathing provides some (but not much) oxygen to prevent tissues, particularly the brain, from dying.


        </item>
        <item>
                CPR for Infants (Under 1 Year) \n\n\n

1. Assess the situation to figure out if their airway is blocked. The most common cause of infant suffocation is choking. You need to assess the situation to determine if the airway is completely blocked or only partially blocked.
\n\n● If the baby is coughing or gagging, the airway is partially blocked. Let the baby continue to cough, as this is the best way to dislodge the blockage.
\n● If the baby is not able to cough and begins to turn bright red or blue, the airway is completely blocked. You will need to perform back blows and chest compressions to dislodge the blockage.
\n● If your baby is ill, having an allergic reaction, or suffocating because their airway is swollen, you can perform chest compressions and rescue breaths, but you will need to call local emergency services immediately.
\n\n2. Position the baby between your forearms. Position the baby so that they are face-up on 1 forearm. Cradle the back of their head with the hand of the same forearm. Place your other forearm over the baby s front and gently turn them over so that they are face-down, remaining sandwiched in between your arms the entire time.
\n\n● Use your thumb and fingers to hold the jaw as you turn the baby.
\n● Lower your bottom arm onto your thigh. The baby s head should be lower than their chest.
\n● Note that back blows should only be delivered if the baby is still conscious. If the baby falls unconscious, skip the back blows and proceed straight to the chest compressions and rescue breaths.
\n\n
3. Deliver back blows to dislodge an airway obstruction. Use the heel of your dominant hand to deliver 5 gentle yet distinct back blows in between the baby s shoulder blades.
\n\n● Continue to support the baby s neck and head by holding their jaw between your thumb and forefingers.
\n● Giving CPR to a baby is often walking a fine line between being effective and causing injury. However, a minor muscular injury is a small price to pay for saving a life.
\n\n
4. Place the baby on their back. After delivering the gentle back blows, place your free hand on the back of the baby s head, resting your arm firmly along the baby s spine. Carefully turn the baby back over so they are face-up again.
\n\n● Don t lift the baby s head as you turn them, as this can force the clog back into their throat. Keep the head down.
\n● The baby should remain sandwiched in between your arms as you turn them.
\n● Remember to remain calm and talk soothingly to the baby. They can t comprehend your words, but they can pick up on your calm and loving tone.
\n\n5.Position your fingers in the center of the baby s chest. Position the tips of 2 or 3 fingers in the center of the baby s chest while supporting the baby s neck and head with your other hand. Use your thumb and fingers to hold the jaw as you sandwich the baby in between your forearms. The lower arm should support the baby s back on your opposite thigh, and the baby s head should be lower than the rest of their body.
\n\n● You could also place the baby on their back on a firm, flat surface, like a table or the floor.
\n● The fingers should be placed in between the baby s nipples at the center of their chest.
\n\n
6. Gently compress the chest. Push straight down on the chest, depressing it by about 1.5 inches (3.8 cm). If the baby is conscious, only perform 5 compressions. If the baby is unconscious, perform 30 compressions.
\n\n● Pump rapidly at a rate of 100 compressions per minute.
\n● Each compression should be smooth, not abrupt or shaky.
\n● Be careful not to injure the baby s ribs during the compressions.
\n\n7. Cover the baby s nose and mouth and breathe. You do not need to pinch the nose plugged as you would do with an adult. Instead, seal off the baby s breathing passages by placing your entire mouth over their nose and mouth. Make sure to wipe away any vomit, blood, mucus, or saliva first.
\n\n● Give 2 gentle rescue breaths. Deliver 1 puff of air into the baby s mouth. If the chest moves, deliver the second puff of air.
\n● If the chest does not move, attempt to clear the airway again before administering the second breath.
\n● Do not deliver deep breaths of air from your lungs. Instead, use the muscles in your cheeks to deliver gentle puffs of air.
\n\n
8. Repeat the cycle as needed. Repeat chest compressions and rescue breaths as needed until the baby begins to breathe again or until emergency medical professionals arrive.
\n\n● If you suspect that the baby is choking on a foreign object, you should look into their mouth after every round of chest compressions.
\n● Each cycle should consist of 30 chest compressions followed by 2 emergency breaths.



        </item>
        <item>
                How to Defending Yourself from Snakes \n\n\n

                1. Wear protective clothing when you re in snake territory. If you re out hiking in a snake-friendly environment e.g., the American southwest—wear protective clothing including long pants, tall hiking boots that cover your ankles, long sleeves, and gloves.
\n\n● Long pants and hiking boots will prevent the snake s fangs from penetrating your skin if one happens to bite you.

\n\n
2. Back up from a venomous snake if it s in a striking position. If the snake is coiled and has raised its head up, it s in striking position and could strike at you at any moment. Don t turn your back on the snake and don t run. Instead, back away from the snake at a normal walking pace until you re at least 20 feet (6.1 m) away.
\n\n● While you should still back away from a snake that s extended full-length, it s less urgent. The snake will need to pause and coil its body before striking you.
\n\n
3. Fend off the snake with a walking stick if it moves towards you. Always take a walking stick or trekking pole with you when you hike in snake country. As you’re backing away, if the snake slithers or strikes in your direction, use your walking stick to fend the snake off. Try to hook the end of the stick under one of the snake s coils and fling it far away from you and your group.
\n\n● Choose a stick at least 4 feet (1.2 m) long.
\n\n
4. Administer first aid if you or your companion are bitten. Keep the bitten limb lower than the individual’s heart to prevent venom from being distributed throughout the person’s body. Wrap a compression bandage around the bitten limb, and get to the nearest hospital as fast as possible.
\n\n● If you re with an individual who is bitten, do not attempt to suck the venom from the wound! Also do not cut the wound open with a pocket knife in an attempt to drain out the venom.
\n● These strategies are both bad advice and will end up harming the person who has been bitten.
\n\n5. Wrap an arm around your ribs if a constricting snake loops around you. As soon as a snake begins to constrict even if it’s just being curious hold your non-dominant arm against your rib cage. If you relax as the snake loops around you, it may not attempt to constrict you. In fact, the snake may just be curious. Struggling, however, prompts the snake to squeeze. So, remain still and don’t panic.
\n\n● Struggling also communicates to the snake that you’re edible prey. If you remain static, the snake will not be sure if you’re edible and should move off.
\n● Having an arm against your chest will also prevent the snake from forcing air out of your lungs with its constrictions.
\n\n
6. Grab the snake s head with your free hand and unwind it if it s wrapped around you. It s important that you don t let the snake wrap itself around both of your hands. Keep your non-dominant hand pinned against your chest. Then, grab the snake around its head or neck with your other hand and pull the constricting snake backward. Unwind the coiling snake by unlooping the tight layers of the snake’s coiled body.[24]
\n\n● If you re with a group of people, ask them to help you unwind the snake s body.

        </item>


    </string-array>
</resources>